JASON MALKIN

767 Las Palmas Drive, Irvine CA 92602 (714) 913-3216 jasonamalkin@gmail.com

STRATEGIC ANALYSIS & REPORTING

Polished young professional with 5 years internal and external reporting experience who undertakes complex assignments, meets tight deadlines and delivers superior performance. Demonstrated ability to work on project teams, build relationships across the company and influence business decisions. Applies strong financial planning and analytical skills to inform executive level management of industry specific trends, forecasted performance and actual results. Operates with a strong sense of urgency and thrives in a fast-paced setting. **Core competencies include**:

- Advanced Excel (e.g. Pivot Tables, V-Lookups)
- Technical Accounting Research & Application
- US GAAP, External and Internal Financial Reporting
- Oracle, SAP, MRI, JD Edwards, Hyperion, NetSuite, and Timberline
- Derivatives and Hedging Programs
- Project Management and Process Improvement
- Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis
- Strong Written and Verbal Communication

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kaiser Aluminum Corporation – Foothill Ranch, Ca

Financial Reporting Analyst

3/2016 - 6/2017*

- *reduction in force, department re-organization
 - Responsible for preparing quarterly financial statements, footnote disclosures and XBRL tagging in accordance with U.S. GAAP for 10Q/K SEC filings
 - Prepared accounting entries and reconciliations for cash, derivative and short-term investment transactions
 - Created dashboards to monitor settlement, mark to market gain/loss and credit availability for over 1,000 derivative instruments and short-term investments
 - Researched FASB guidance on newly issued accounting standards and their projected effect on the Company
 - Published memorandums to establish policy on newly issued accounting standards
 - Researched and resolved discrepancies in derivative valuations between the Company and multiple brokers
 - Reviewed financial data consistency in press releases and performed fair value hierarchy testing on all Company financial instruments (i.e. derivatives, available for sale securities and long term debt)
 - Prepared quarterly P&L and Balance Sheet analytic presentations for external auditors and Audit Committee

Key accomplishments include:

- Slashed department month end close from 5 to 3 days through advanced report customization in MS Excel
- Managed overhaul of multiple business processes and internal controls related to derivatives, off-balance sheet commitments and fair value reporting through creation of process narratives and desktop procedures
- Created relationship driven partnership with plant operations leaders to implement various reporting procedures (i.e. disclosure of metal purchases against newly instituted cash flow hedge program, scrap and prime metal purchases)

Various Companies and Locations

7/2014 - 3/2016

Accounting and Finance Contractor

Worked with a wide range of businesses in various industries to rapidly expand knowledge of reporting processes and build valuable technical skills. **Companies include:**

The Warmington Group of Companies – Costa Mesa, Ca

- Built investment underwriting models for new acquisition opportunities
- Prepared budgets and forecasts supporting projects under construction and future developments
- Perform a variety of econometric studies and assist in due diligence effort during land acquisition process

Matt White Custom Homes - Costa Mesa, Ca

Prepared accounting entries and reconciliations for new home projects under construction

JASON MALKIN

767 Las Palmas Drive, Irvine CA 92602 (714) 913-3216 jasonamalkin@gmail.com

Managed all job cost functions (i.e. project reporting, bid spreads, change orders, loan draws and vendor invoicing)

Western Digital Corporation - Irvine, CA

- Prepared annual financial statements and footnote disclosures in accordance with U.S. GAAP for SEC filings
- Assisted in the coordination and preparation of internal reporting materials to support quarterly audit
- Worked with teams to integrate regulated subsidiaries under ASC 805 (Business Combinations)

HSF Affiliates - Irvine, CA

Responsible for analyzing credit, resolving collection issues and preparing financial reports for franchise customers

Worldview Travel - Santa Ana, CA

 Managed all accounting functions, including journal entries, reconciliations, payables, and an annual statutory audit for 10 branch offices across the United States

Broadcom - Irvine, CA

- Assisted in overhaul of global fixed asset life cycle management of \$1 billion in assets to improve acquisition, physical inventory, trade-in and disposal processes
- Identified and calculated impairment losses under ASC 360 (Property, Plant and Equipment)
- Partnered with teams to dispose of mobile device business unit in accordance with ASC 420 (Restructuring), ASC 360 (Assets Held for Sale) and ASC 205 (Discontinued Operations)

Irvine Company - Newport Beach, Ca

10/2013 - 6/2014

Project Accountant

- Responsible for job cost reporting for 11 apartment projects under a \$ 2.3 billion-dollar budget
- Prepared accounting entries and reconciliations for all projects under construction
- Worked with Construction Managers to process loan draws, bid spreads and change orders

Douglas Emmett Management- Santa Monica, Ca

4/2012 - 10/2013

Staff Accountant

- Managed all accounting functions for a diverse portfolio of Class A commercial and residential properties
- Ensured proper execution of residential and commercial leases, reconciled cash and various balance sheet accounts
- Worked with Property Managers to research delinquencies, open credits and security deposit variances

VOLUNTEER AND COMMUNITY SERVICE:

2011 Tutor, The Academic Advantage

Tutored children in low-income neighborhoods, assessing their academic strengths and weaknesses in between accounting consulting engagements

2010 Intern/Clerk, Santa Barbara Courthouse & District Attorney's Office

Assisted Deputy Attorney's with case proceedings; Served as a Judge's legal clerk while preparing for Law School

2006 Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America

High School Renovation Project: Coached into an opportunity which would teach me to delegate to younger scouts. Demonstrated ability to delegate, teach skills and develop team work

EDUCATION:

B.A., Business Economics – University of California, Santa Barbara